Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Catherine and today we have a very painful lesson for you.
我是Catherine，今天我们为大家准备了一堂非常痛苦的课。
That's right.
没错。
Today we're going to go to one of the worst places for me.
今天我们要去一个对我来说最糟糕的地方之一。
We're going to go to the dentist.
我们要去看牙医。
Okay, so the person in this dialogue has a pain in their mouth, in the tooth area.
好的，这段对话中的人嘴巴疼，牙疼。
So let's take a listen to this dialogue and when we come back, we'll be talking a little
所以让我们先听一下这段对话，等我们回来后再详细讨论。
bit more about it.
再聊一聊。
What seems to be the problem?
有什么问题吗？
I have a really bad toothache.
我牙疼得厉害。
My cheek is swollen and I can't eat anything.
我的脸颊肿了，什么都吃不了。
Let's have a look.
让我看看。
This doesn't look too good.
情况看起来不太好。
I think we may have to pull out your wisdom tooth.
我想我们可能需要拔掉你的智齿。
It's pressing against your molars and that's one of the reasons you're experiencing so
它正压着你的臼齿，这也是你感到这么疼的原因之一。
much pain.
疼得这么厉害。
When you pull my tooth, will you also have to extract the nerve and the root?
拔牙的时候，你也要把神经和牙根抽出来吗？
First we will take some x-rays and see what we're dealing with.
首先我们会拍几张X光片，看看情况如何。
I also noticed a small cavity up front here, so you are going to need a filling.
我还注意到前面这里有个小蛀牙，所以你需要补牙。
I guess that's what I get for not flossing or brushing my teeth three times a day.
我想这就是我不每天用牙线或刷三次牙的后果。
It could be that or maybe you are eating too many sweets.
可能是这个原因，或者你吃太多甜食了。
In any case, I'll administer an anesthetic and you won't feel a thing.
不管怎样，我会给你打麻药，你什么感觉都不会有。
Alright we're back and obviously we're going to take a look at a lot of vocab related to
好了，我们回来了，显然我们要看看很多和看牙医以及经历一点疼痛相关的词汇。
going to the dentist and experiencing a little bit of pain.
经历一点疼痛。
So let's take a look at that in Language Takeaway.
那么让我们在“语言要点”中看看这些。
First up in Language Takeaway today we have the root of the problem.
今天“语言要点”的第一项是问题的根源。
It's a toothache.
是牙痛。
That's right, we have a really bad toothache.
没错，我们牙疼得厉害。
Okay well ache means pain or soreness and tooth is your tooth.
好的，“ache”意思是疼痛或酸痛，“tooth”就是你的牙齿。
So I could say, oh gosh I have a really bad toothache.
所以我可以这么说，哦天哪，我牙疼得厉害。
That's right, that means your tooth or your teeth hurt.
没错，那意味着你的牙齿疼。
And basically you can combine it like a stomachache or headache.
基本上你可以像“stomachache”或“headache”那样组合。
Backache.
背痛。
That's right.
没错。
So usually when you have a toothache, you experience different symptoms, different things
所以通常当你牙疼时，你会经历不同的症状，不同的事情。
happen to you.
发生在你身上。
What's one of these things Marco?
Marco，其中一件事是什么？
Well in this case the girl had a swollen cheek.
在这个例子里，那个女孩脸颊肿了。
Her cheek is swollen.
她的脸颊肿了。
So the cheek is the side of the face.
所以“cheek”是脸的两侧。
It's usually where it's a little bit pink and when your cheek is swollen, it looks puffy.
通常是有点粉红的地方，当你的脸颊肿了，它看起来鼓鼓的。
It looks bigger than normal.
看起来比正常大。
That's right.
没错。
So for example sometimes you fall and you hurt your finger and it'll get fat and it'll
所以比如有时候你摔倒，伤到手指，它会变胖，会像你说的那样鼓起来。
get puffy as you say.
鼓起来。
It's swollen.
它肿了。
That's right.
没错。
So anything can be swollen really.
所以实际上任何东西都可能肿。
When you hit your toe on something hard and your toe later gets bigger, it's swollen.
当你把脚趾撞到硬物上，后来脚趾变大，那就是肿了。
That's right.
没错。
So obviously her cheek is swollen and she has a toothache because apparently her wisdom
所以显然她的脸颊肿了，她牙疼，因为显然她的智齿。
teeth or her wisdom tooth is coming out.
她的智齿正在长出来。
All right.
好的。
So wisdom teeth are special teeth.
所以智齿是特殊的牙齿。
I don't know if they actually have anything to do with wisdom which means being smart.
我不知道它们是否真的和“wisdom”有关，“wisdom”意思是聪明。
To be wise.
变得明智。
Wise.
明智。
But wisdom teeth are those four teeth in the very, very, very back of your mouth.
但智齿是你嘴巴最最最后面的四颗牙齿。
That's right.
没错。
So these are the last teeth that come in or the last teeth that grow in your mouth.
所以这些是最后长出来的牙齿，或者最后在你嘴里生长的牙齿。
So I think usually you're 18 or 20 when they come in.
所以我想通常你18或20岁时它们长出来。
That's right.
没错。
A lot of people experience these when they're older.
很多人年纪大些时经历这些。
Maybe that's why they call them wisdom teeth because you're older and you're wiser.
也许这就是为什么它们叫智齿，因为你年纪大了，更明智了。
I had them when I was about 14, 13.
我大约14、13岁时就长了。
I was very young.
我很年轻。
But these come in the very back.
但这些长在最里面。
They're the furthest away from your lips.
它们离嘴唇最远。
Okay.
好的。
Very good.
很好。
So when they come in, sometimes there's not enough space and so they start to press against
所以当它们长出来时，有时空间不够，所以它们开始挤压。
the other teeth in your mouth, specifically against your molars.
你嘴里的其他牙齿，特别是你的臼齿。
So molars are other teeth.
所以“molars”是其他牙齿。
These are also in the back of your mouth.
这些也在你嘴巴的后部。
You can tell which ones are molars I believe because they're flat on top.
我相信你可以分辨哪些是臼齿，因为它们顶部是平的。
They look like a little square.
它们看起来像个小方块。
Those are the ones that you use to chew your food with mostly.
这些是你主要用来咀嚼食物的牙齿。
Exactly.
没错。
They're not pointy like your front teeth.
它们不像你的门牙那样尖。
And so molars are in the back of your mouth.
所以臼齿在口腔的后部。
Wisdom teeth are in the very back of your mouth.
智齿在口腔的最深处。
And molars can be very sore when the wisdom teeth push against them.
当智齿挤压臼齿时，臼齿会非常疼痛。
And so in this case, you will have to take your teeth out or the dentist will take your
所以在这种情况下，你必须拔掉牙齿，或者牙医会拔掉你的
teeth out.
牙齿。
But what's something we say when we talk about taking the whole tooth out?
但当我们说拔掉整颗牙齿时，我们用什么词呢？
Well, in this case, he's going to extract the tooth, but also he's going to extract
嗯，在这种情况下，他要拔掉牙齿，而且还要拔掉
the nerve and the root.
神经和牙根。
Okay.
好的。
So nerves are parts of our bodies.
神经是我们身体的一部分。
We can't see them, but they help us feel things.
我们看不见它们，但它们帮助我们感知事物。
So maybe when someone hits me, the nerves in my arm, they tell my brain that it hurts.
所以，如果有人打我，我手臂里的神经会告诉我的大脑很疼。
Well, we also have nerves in our teeth and that's what we're talking about here.
嗯，我们的牙齿里也有神经，这就是我们这里讨论的。
But what's this other thing?
但另一个东西是什么？
You talked about the nerve and the root.
你提到了神经和牙根。
It's very similar to a plant, for example.
这很像植物，比如说。
You consider that your teeth are like plants and they have little roots that go into your
你可以把牙齿想象成植物，它们有小小的牙根伸进你的
gums.
牙龈。
And this is how basically you get teeth stay alive.
这基本上就是牙齿保持活力的方式。
They are fed basically by your body.
它们基本上由你的身体供养。
All right.
好的。
So root, like with a tree or a plant, is the very bottom of something.
所以牙根，就像树或植物一样，是某物的最底部。
And in this case, to extract means to take out or to take away.
在这种情况下，拔除意味着取出或移除。
So the dentist will have to extract the root and the nerve.
所以牙医必须拔除牙根和神经。
So that sounds pretty painful.
听起来很疼。
It's painful, but they have to do it, right?
是疼，但他们必须这么做，对吧？
So when the dentist has to extract the tooth, in this case, the nerve and the root and everything,
所以当牙医必须拔牙时，在这种情况下，拔掉神经、牙根和所有东西，
in order for you not to feel it, he gives you special drugs.
为了让你不感到疼痛，他会给你一些特殊的药物。
What are these drugs called?
这些药物叫什么？
These are called anesthetics.
这些叫做麻醉剂。
Okay.
好的。
So most people, when they are having major surgery, they get anesthetics so that they
所以大多数人，在做大手术时，会使用麻醉剂，这样他们
can't feel anything.
就感觉不到任何东西。
Remember, we were just talking about nerves.
记得我们刚才在讨论神经。
Well, anesthetics make it so that you can't feel things through your nerves.
嗯，麻醉剂让你无法通过神经感知事物。
That's right.
没错。
So obviously you don't want to feel the pain when somebody's pulling that tooth out of
所以显然你不想在别人把牙齿从你嘴里拔出来时感到疼痛。
your mouth.
你的嘴。
So you get an anesthetic and then you don't really feel anything.
所以你用了麻醉剂，然后就感觉不到什么了。
You kind of feel something, but you don't really feel pain.
你会有点感觉，但不会真的感到疼痛。
Exactly.
正是。
So anesthetic basically makes you numb.
所以麻醉剂基本上让你麻木。
Numb.
麻木。
That's right.
没错。
That's the word, numb.
就是这个词，麻木。
Okay.
好的。
So we've taken a look at a lot of vocab, molars, wisdom teeth, etc.
我们看了很多词汇，臼齿、智齿等等。
Why don't we listen to the dialogue again and we'll be back in a bit with Fluency Builder.
我们为什么不重新听一遍对话，稍后回来进行流利度训练。
What seems to be the problem?
有什么问题吗？
I have a really bad toothache.
我牙疼得厉害。
My cheek is swollen and I can't eat anything.
我的脸颊肿了，什么都吃不了。
Let's have a look.
让我看看。
Hmm, this doesn't look too good.
嗯，情况不太好。
I think we may have to pull out your wisdom tooth.
我想我们可能得拔掉你的智齿。
It's pressing against your molars and that's one of the reasons you're experiencing so
它正挤压着你的臼齿，这也是你感到这么
much pain.
疼的原因之一。
When you pull my tooth, will you also have to extract the nerve and the root?
拔牙的时候，你也要拔掉神经和牙根吗？
First we will take some x-rays and see what we're dealing with.
我们先拍几张X光片，看看情况。
I also noticed a small cavity up front here.
我还注意到前面这里有个小蛀牙。
So you are going to need a filling.
所以你需要补牙。
I guess that's what I get for not flossing or brushing my teeth three times a day.
我想这就是我不每天用牙线或刷三次牙的后果。
It could be that.
可能是这个原因。
Or maybe you are eating too many sweets.
或者你吃太多甜食了。
In any case, I'll administer an anesthetic and you won't feel a thing.
不管怎样，我会给你用麻醉剂，你什么都不会感觉到。
Alright, so the topic of today's lesson is toothache but it's also basically about learning
好的，今天课程的主题是牙疼，但基本上也是关于学习
that you will have to have your tooth taken out.
你将不得不拔牙。
So to say this we say, to pull out a tooth.
所以要说这个，我们说，拔牙。
Okay, so that's what the dentist said.
好的，这就是牙医说的。
I think we may have to pull out your wisdom tooth.
我想我们可能得拔掉你的智齿。
Not good news.
不是好消息。
Okay, so to pull out means to extract.
好的，所以拔掉意味着取出。
So just remember here this is a phrase that has pull out.
所以记住，这是一个包含“拔掉”的短语。
Out would be the preposition here.
“掉”在这里是介词。
We wouldn't say pull off or pull at.
我们不会说“拔开”或“拔向”。
We'd say pull out.
我们会说“拔掉”。
Like for example, you can pull out a hair or your hair.
比如，你可以拔掉一根头发或你的头发。
Exactly.
正是。
Okay, so we're pulling out the wisdom tooth and the dentist first wants to take some x-rays
好的，所以我们拔掉智齿，牙医首先想拍几张X光片
to see what we're dealing with.
看看情况。
Okay, so to deal with something means to work on it or to have something to do with.
好的，所以“deal with something”意思是处理某事或与某事有关。
And so in this case the dentist wants to know, is this serious?
所以在这个例子中，牙医想知道的是：这严重吗？
What are we dealing with here?
我们这里面对的是什么情况？
That's right.
没错。
So he's trying to judge the situation.
所以他是在试图判断情况。
So maybe what would be another scenario or another situation where you would say, I have
那么，可能还有哪些场景或情况你会说“我得看看我们面对的是什么”？
to see what we're dealing with.
我得看看我们面对的是什么。
Well, in the case of the weather and the newsmen who report about the weather, maybe they see
嗯，在天气和播报天气的新闻播报员的情况下，他们可能看到风暴要来了，但必须看雷达和电脑屏幕来了解他们面对的是什么。
that a storm is coming but they have to look at the radars and the computer screens to
他们必须看雷达和电脑屏幕来了解他们面对的是什么。
see what they're dealing with.
他们面对的是什么。
Is it a serious storm or is it a very weak storm?
是严重的风暴还是微弱的风暴？
They have to evaluate.
他们必须评估。
That's right.
没错。
Okay, very good.
好的，非常好。
And so we're going to see what we're dealing with.
所以我们要看看我们面对的是什么。
And then the girl I think knows that she hasn't really taken good care of her teeth.
然后那个女孩，我觉得她知道她没有好好照顾自己的牙齿。
And so she says, I guess that's what I get for not flossing or brushing my teeth.
所以她说：“我猜这就是我不使用牙线或不刷牙的下场。”
So that's what you get or that's what I get.
所以“that's what you get”或“that's what I get”。
Where the pronoun changes, I, you, he, that's what I get for not taking care of myself.
代词会变化，我、你、他，“这就是我不照顾自己的下场”。
This means it's my fault.
这意思是这是我的错。
I deserved it.
我活该。
I deserve this thing.
我应得的。
So I could say, Marco, that's what you get for not doing your homework.
所以我可以这么说，Marco，这就是你不做作业的下场。
You got a bad grade on your test.
你考试得了低分。
That's right.
没错。
So it's basically a way of saying, that's what you deserve.
所以这基本上是一种说法，意思是“这就是你应得的”。
That's the consequence for your actions.
这是你行为的后果。
Exactly.
正是。
Okay.
好的。
And what about our last phrase?
那我们最后一个短语呢？
This is something that I hate to hear from doctors and dentists because usually it's
这是我最讨厌从医生和牙医那里听到的话，因为通常都是谎言。
a lie.
这是谎言。
A dentist will say before he gives you a shot or before he takes your tooth out, you won't
牙医在给你打针或拔牙前会说：“你一点感觉都不会有。”
feel a thing.
你一点感觉都不会有。
That's right.
没错。
So he's basically saying you're not going to feel any pain.
所以他基本上是在说你不会感到任何疼痛。
But why do we say you won't feel a thing instead of you won't feel anything?
但为什么我们说“you won't feel a thing”而不是“you won't feel anything”？
Just a set phrase.
只是一个固定短语。
It's something we say, I would remember it like this because it's more likely to be said
这是我们常说的，我会这样记住它，因为这样说的可能性更大。
in this way.
这样说的可能性更大。
You won't feel a thing.
你一点感觉都不会有。
I think it basically means not even one little thing, you're not going to feel that.
我认为它基本上意思是连一点点东西都不会，你不会感觉到。
So for example, I'm about to fix someone's back, you know, when you have to pull them
所以比如，我正要帮别人调整背部，你知道，当你需要拉他们让他们的背感觉好点时。
and make their back feel better.
当你需要拉他们让他们的背感觉好点时。
I say, you won't feel a thing.
我会说：“你一点感觉都不会有。”
You fix their back.
你调整他们的背。
Okay.
好的。
So you won't feel a thing or you won't feel anything.
所以“you won't feel a thing”或“you won't feel anything”。
Both are correct, but I think it's more common to hear you won't feel a thing.
两种都对，但我认为更常听到的是“you won't feel a thing”。
Okay.
好的。
So why don't we go back?
那我们为什么不回去呢？
Let's take one last look at our dialogue and we'll be back in a bit.
让我们最后再看一遍我们的对话，我们一会儿回来。
What seems to be the problem?
有什么问题吗？
I have a really bad toothache.
我牙疼得很厉害。
My cheek is swollen and I can't eat anything.
我的脸颊肿了，什么都吃不了。
Let's have a look.
让我看看。
Hmm.
嗯。
This doesn't look too good.
这看起来不太好。
I think we may have to pull out your wisdom tooth.
我想我们可能得拔掉你的智齿。
It's pressing against your molars and that's one of the reasons you're experiencing so
它正压着你的臼齿，这也是你感到这么疼的原因之一。
much pain.
这也是你感到这么疼的原因之一。
When you pull my tooth, will you also have to extract the nerve and the root?
你拔我牙的时候，是不是也要抽掉神经和牙根？
First we will take some x-rays and see what we're dealing with.
首先我们会拍些X光片，看看我们面对的是什么情况。
I also noticed a small cavity up front here, so you are going to need a filling.
我还注意到前面这里有个小蛀洞，所以你需要补牙。
I guess that's what I get for not flossing or brushing my teeth three times a day.
我猜这就是我不每天用牙线或刷牙三次的下场。
It could be that.
可能是这个原因。
Or maybe you are eating too many sweets.
或者你吃太多甜食了。
In any case, I'll administer an anesthetic and you won't feel a thing.
不管怎样，我会给你打麻药，你一点感觉都不会有。
All right so talking about dentists and talking about wisdom teeth, you say that you still
好的，说到牙医和智齿，你说你还有四颗智齿。
have all four wisdom teeth.
你还有四颗智齿。
I do.
是的。
They're all still back there.
它们都还在后面。
So you didn't need to have them taken out or pulled?
所以你不需要把它们拔掉？
No, as my dentist likes to say, I have a big mouth.
不需要，就像我的牙医喜欢说的，我嘴巴大。
Which in English has two meanings.
这在英语里有两个意思。
A big mouth is not just a large mouth, but also it means you like to talk a lot.
“大嘴巴”不仅指嘴巴大，还指你话多。
Right.
对。
So, but did you ever have braces for example when you were a kid?
那么，你小时候戴过牙套吗？
Oh yes.
哦，戴过。
Oh you had braces.
哦，你戴过牙套。
I had a retainer, which is a device that you, it looks like a line across your teeth and
我戴过保持器，那是一种装置，看起来就像一条线横在你的牙齿上，
you put it in usually at night, but sometimes during the day and it makes some space in
通常晚上戴，但有时白天也戴，它能在你的嘴里腾出一些空间。
your mouth.
你的嘴里。
But I also had braces after that.
但之后我还戴过牙套。
I hated braces.
我讨厌牙套。
I had them for two years.
我戴了两年。
Why did you hate braces?
你为什么讨厌牙套？
Because they're uncomfortable.
因为它们不舒服。
Well, they don't look very good, especially when you're a 13 year old girl and you want
嗯，它们看起来也不好看，尤其当你是个13岁的女孩，想显得可爱，
to look cute and you have this big metal thing in your mouth.
嘴里却塞着这么个大金属玩意儿。
That's right.
没错。
Did you have braces?
你戴过牙套吗？
No, no, I never had braces.
没有，没有，我从没戴过牙套。
Actually it was kind of for a while, I think a lot of people thought it was cool to have
其实有一阵子，我觉得很多人觉得戴牙套很酷。
braces.
牙套。
I did not grow up where you grew up.
我成长的地方和你不一样。
It was not cool where I grew up.
在我长大的地方，戴牙套可不酷。
I don't know.
我不知道。
I think, or it gets to a point where in certain parts, I guess my school was filled with kids
我觉得，或者说在某些地方，大概我的学校全是戴牙套的孩子。
that had braces.
都戴着牙套。
So I guess everyone just had really bad teeth.
所以我猜大家牙齿都很糟糕。
So obviously the people that didn't have braces kind of were left aside.
所以显然那些没戴牙套的人就被晾在一边了。
So you're like, oh, I want braces.
所以你就会想，哦，我想要牙套。
I want to be part of the group.
我想成为群体的一员。
I know sometimes I wish I had glasses, because everyone I know has glasses.
我知道有时候我希望自己戴眼镜，因为我认识的人都有眼镜。
Really?
真的吗？
Yeah.
是啊。
If you have good vision though.
不过如果你视力好的话。
Yeah, it sucks to be perfect, right?
是啊，完美也挺烦的，对吧？
Well, this is a really interesting topic and going to the dentist is always complicated.
嗯，这真是个有趣的话题，看牙医总是很复杂。
Maybe some of our listeners are dentists themselves or they have some stories that they can share
也许我们的一些听众本身就是牙医，或者他们有些故事可以分享
with us.
给我们。
Please let us know what you're thinking and share your dentist stories with us on EnglishPod.com.
请告诉我们你的想法，并在EnglishPod.com上分享你的牙医故事。
We'll be waiting for you there.
我们会在那里等你。
All right.
好的。
We'll see you guys then.
那我们到时候见。
Bye.
再见。